# **Christopher Barden**

Expert in the areas of problem solving, communications, decision making and leadership. Entrepreneurial background provides a deep level of passion for innovation, optimistic approaches and being assertive enough to take calculated risk as I execute along an *intrapreneurial* path toward creating customer joy. Vast experience with accounting principles and software products including Quickbooks.

Utilize lean systems to refine processes and nurture managers to become more effective business leaders as they increase diversity in talent and decision making that supports continuous improvement.

# **Areas of Expertise**

Systems Design and Implementation Project Management & Quality Control

#### **Education**

M.S., Global Business Systems

- University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI
- 2001

B.A., Business Administration

- Spring Arbor College, Spring Arbor, MI
- 1987

#### **Licenses and Certifications**

Certificate in Robotics – LCC, 1985 MCSE NT 4.0 CNE Intranetware 4.11 CCNA Network Administrator CISSP Information Securities Six Sigma Green Belt

## **Publications and Awards**

Hottest PC Build – PC World, 1995 Achiever of the Year - Jr. Achieve., 2000 Effectiveness Equation – IQA, 2003 Standards Award – SEI, 2005 Product Innovation of the Year – ISSA, 2005

### **Affiliations**

Society of Engineers, 1982
3-Com Business Partner, 1993
Meridian Area Business Assn., 2004
MI Economic Development Corp., 2006
Meridian Econ. Dev., 2008
Kettering Entrepreneurial Society, 2015
Founding Member Intrapreneurial Conference

#### Software/Hardware

PC/Apple Server and Workstation OS Disaster Recovery/Forensic Analysis Graphic/Video/Audio Development Programming/Web Development Shop Floor/Inventory Control Systems Accounting/Job Costing/P&L Analysis (Quickbooks/Peachtree/Sage/MAS)

## **Prior Experience**

Business Consultant, PC Complete, Inc. (Practical Consulting) (1984 – present)

Leading a successful, multi-site technology and business consulting organization serving the Mid-Michigan area. We offer specialized services including business planning, marketing, process engineering, management controls, performance indicators, applications programming, product development and quality systems.

Interim Operations Manager, CLEAResult Consulting, Inc. East Lansing, MI (2014 – 2017)

As operations manager, I designed and delivered innovative change management programs, facilitated continuous improvement through the redesign of internal operating and business processes, and took a proactive approach in successful organization and team development initiatives that delivered consistent and sustainable operating revenue, profit, and quality.

*Interim VP of Marketing & Product Development, Foote-Mats, Inc.* (2004 – 2006)

Leaned against my experience in startups and business development to create a Best-in-Class manufacturer / Distributor of Jan-San products. Received several patents and awards for my product designs and innovations.

Interim Executive Function Leader/Director IT, DCP (1997 - 2004)

Facilitated organizational change and provided expertise on technical and functional business topics. Implemented a multimillion dollar ERP system, executed lean business & manufacturing systems and worked with senior management to develop strategic development initiatives that were in alignment with the corporate vision and mission.

Volunteer, Ingham Medical – Stroke Rehab (1985 - 2001)